Aleksei Bochkov, 25 y.o.

SUMMARY

After working as a private tutor (including teaching iOS development) and as a project manager in a big company I started to develop iOS applications. Worked in outsourcing, freelance and created many apps in Apple Developer Academy. Also participated in hackathons and challenges. With all my energy, skills, ideas and experience now I want to take a part in an interesting and useful project.

SKILLS

- Swift, UIKit (Storyboard and AutoLayout), SwiftUI, CoreData, XCFrameworks, Alamofire, SocketIO, SpriteKit, MapKit, CoreLocation, Localization, CoreBluetooth, CocoaPods, Swift Package Manager, Notification Center, StoreKit, AVFoundation, CallDirectory, MVC, MVP, MVVM, watchOS, Sentry.
- · Git, JIRA, Algorithms, Further Mathematics, Python, C++, Kotlin, Java, SQL.
- · Agile, Scrum, Kanban, Scrumban, Project management, Communication, Presentation, Public speaking, Teamwork.

EXPERIENCE

Chief Technology Officer

Goody band

July 2021 - Present, Saint-Petersburg, Russia

- · In this startup I was responsible for the whole development process. I developed an iOS app. architectured backend and managed a team of 5 developers.
- · Main tools: UIKit, SpriteKit, CoreData, Alamofire, SocketIO, CIFilter, AVFoundation, MVC, Git, JIRA.

iOS developer

Emphasoft

February 2020 - July 2021, Saint-Petersburg, Russia

- · As one of two iOS developers in the company I held a wide range of duties. Specifically, I developed several utility, service and financial applications from scratch, as well as, supported some of the older company projects.
- For instance, I added new features, fixed bugs and updated app Repay. It's a financial tool which helps to keep an eye on your expenses with friends. Also from a scratch I developed Atmocube: a service product for bluetooth device which scans air around.
- $\cdot \ Main\ tools: UIKit, XCF rameworks, CoreBluetooth, Notification Center, StoreKit, Call Directory, MVP, MVVM, Git, JIRA. A storekey of the property of the$

Project manager

Tinkoff

July 2018 - July 2019, Saint-Petersburg, Russia

- In one of the biggest fintech companies in the world I managed the team, made business decisions based on the analytical data from the enterprise data warehouse. Our team of backend developers, frontend developers, QA engineers and designers developed a website for a clients personal account.
- · Main tools: SQL, JIRA, Agile, Scrum, Kanban, Scrumban, Project management, Communication, Presentation, Public speaking.

COURSEWORK

Apple Developer Academy

University of Federico II, Naples, Italy · 2022

During an academic year I studied Swift, design, business and applied my knowledges to creating great apps in a team.

TOP PROJECTS

PartyHardy

SwiftUI Jam · November 2021 - Present

- With 1 designer and 1 another iOS software engineer we participated in SwiftUI Jam and in two days developed first version of SwiftUI app PartyHardy. After that we published it in the AppStore and we keep updating it.
- PartyHardy calculates amount of food and drinks you need to order for a party based on the input from the user. App contains share feature, nice onboarding, simple UI and beautiful illustrations.

BubblesSelection

Apple Developer Academy • April 2022 - April 2022

- During personal challenge I developed BubblesSelection SDK which can be uploaded via CocoaPods or Swift Package Manager. This framework helps any developer easily add amazing selection interface to their project. On GitHub I published an app that shows features provided by the SDK.
- $\cdot \ \text{Main tools: UIKit, SpriteKit, AVFoundation, MVC.}\\$

Planet Food

Apple Developer Academy · October 2022 - November 2022

- · Planet Food created as a studying project by a group of 4 people, where I coded most of the application.
- · It stores recipes from all over the world and provides great search features, gamification and saving notes and favourite meals opportunities.
- · Main tools: SwiftUI, UIKit, MapKit, CoreLocation, Combine, MVC, Git.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science

Minor in Mechanics, Mathematics and Programming · Saint-Petersburg State University · Russia · 2018

Exchange student

Minor in Mechanics · Pohang University of Science and Technology · South Korea · 2017

CERTIFICATIONS

Kotlin, Java, Python, C++, Statistics, Probability theory, Biology, Russian history (online courses) Stepik, HyperSkill, Coursera, Openedu.ru · 2019